[{"question":"north","answer":"The direction that is to your left when you are facing the rising sun","guidance":"[nɔːθ] The compass points north. The wind is coming from the north.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737679349},{"question":"transit","answer":"the act of passing through or across a place","guidance":"/'trænzɪt/ The package is in transit.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":1.6599997,"next_review":1738077157},{"question":"outside","answer":"External to","guidance":"[ˌaʊtˈsaɪd, \"He waited outside the building.\", \"The dog is outside.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"countryside","answer":"/ˈkʌntrisaɪd/: the land and scenery of a rural area","guidance":"They moved to the countryside to enjoy a quieter life.","interval":35,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.5799997,"next_review":1740582731},{"question":"corner","answer":"the place where two streets or surfaces meet","guidance":"[ˈkɔrnər, \"The shop is located on the corner of Main Street.\", \"He turned the corner and saw the park.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.3999999,"next_review":1737679321},{"question":"gym","answer":"a place equipped for physical exercise","guidance":"[dʒɪm] I go to the gym every morning. The school has a well-equipped gym.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"harbor","answer":"a place on the coast where ships dock","guidance":"The harbor was filled with fishing boats.","interval":37,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.5799997,"next_review":1740491963},{"question":"sunshine","answer":"/ˈsʌnʃaɪn/: direct sunlight unbroken by cloud, especially over a comparatively large area","guidance":"The weather forecast predicts sunshine for the weekend.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741013092},{"question":"download music","answer":"to transfer music files from the internet to a device","guidance":"/ˌdaʊnˈləʊd ˈmjuːzɪk/ - He downloaded music to listen to on his commute.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738852942},{"question":"yummy","answer":"delicious","guidance":"/ˈjʌmi/: The cake was so yummy that everyone wanted a second piece.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737986281},{"question":"bridge","answer":"a structure carrying a road, path, railway, etc. across a river, road, or other obstacle","guidance":"[brɪdʒ, \"We crossed the bridge over the river.\", \"The old bridge was built in the 18th century.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737643675},{"question":"belly","answer":"The front part of the human trunk below the ribs","guidance":"[ˈbɛli, \"She has a flat belly.\", \"He rubbed his belly after eating.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"rap","answer":"a genre of music with rhythmic speech","guidance":"He is a fan of rap music.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522476},{"question":"singer","answer":"a person who sings","guidance":"The singer has a beautiful voice.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737693214},{"question":"next to","answer":"Adjacent to","guidance":"[nɛkst tuː, \"She lives next to the school.\", \"The store is next to the bank.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"rub","answer":"to move your hand, or something such as a cloth, backwards and forwards over a surface while pressing firmly","guidance":"/rʌb/: She would rub her hands together to keep warm.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3399997,"next_review":1738069429},{"question":"keep fit","answer":"to stay in good physical condition","guidance":"[kiːp fɪt] \"He goes to the gym to keep fit.\" \"Swimming is a great way to keep fit.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.4399998,"next_review":1737381738},{"question":"toast","answer":"sliced bread browned on both sides by exposure to radiant heat","guidance":"[təʊst, \"He had buttered toast for breakfast.\", \"She made toast with jam.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344431},{"question":"taxi","answer":"a car licensed to transport passengers in return for payment of a fare","guidance":"/'tæksi/ We hailed a taxi to get to the hotel.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737466132},{"question":"arrive","answer":"to reach a destination","guidance":"[əˈraɪv, \"They will arrive at the airport at 3 PM.\", \"When you arrive, please call me.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.1599998,"next_review":1737679533},{"question":"stay healthy","answer":"to maintain good health","guidance":"[steɪ ˈhɛlθi] \"She tries to stay healthy by eating well.\" \"Regular exercise helps you stay healthy.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1738076473},{"question":"include","answer":"to contain as part of the whole","guidance":"[ɪnˈkluːd] \"The price includes breakfast.\" \"Please include your contact information.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.4399998,"next_review":1737383366},{"question":"events","answer":"things that happen, especially important or unusual things","guidance":"[ɪˈvɛnts] \"The school hosts several events throughout the year.\" \"Recent events have made us reconsider our plans.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.0599997,"next_review":1737643470},{"question":"match","answer":"a contest in which people or teams compete against each other","guidance":"[mætʃ, \"The football match was very exciting.\", \"She struck a match to light the candle.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"star","answer":"a fixed luminous point in the night sky which is a large, remote incandescent body like the sun","guidance":"[stɑː, \"We looked up at the stars in the night sky.\", \"She is a famous movie star.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"motorcycle","answer":"a two-wheeled vehicle that is powered by a motor and has no pedals","guidance":"[ˈmoʊtərˌsaɪkəl, \"He rides his motorcycle to work every day.\", \"They went on a motorcycle trip across the country.\"]","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738939363},{"question":"study","answer":"to devote time and attention to acquiring knowledge","guidance":"/ˈstʌdi/ - She needs to study for her upcoming exams.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738941360},{"question":"seed","answer":"/siːd/: the unit of reproduction of a flowering plant, capable of developing into another such plant","guidance":"We planted some seeds in the garden.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737608911},{"question":"tablet","answer":"A portable touchscreen computer","guidance":"/'tæblɪt/ \"She read the news on her tablet.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738241951},{"question":"mouse","answer":"A small handheld device that controls a computer's cursor","guidance":"/'maʊs/ \"He clicked on the icon with his mouse.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738241918},{"question":"footprint","answer":"a mark left by a foot or shoe","guidance":"The detective found a footprint near the crime scene.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741013183},{"question":"instrument","answer":"a tool or device used to produce music","guidance":"She learned to play a musical instrument.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741014479},{"question":"adventure","answer":"an unusual and exciting experience","guidance":"[ədˈvɛntʃər, \"They went on an adventure to explore the hidden caves.\", \"Reading can be an adventure of the mind.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.4599998,"next_review":1737553710},{"question":"twig","answer":"a small thin branch of a tree or bush","guidance":"twɪɡ/: She collected small twigs to start the campfire.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737986410},{"question":"hurt","answer":"to cause pain or injury","guidance":"[hɜːt] \"He hurt his knee while playing football.\" \"Does it hurt when you touch it?\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737383778},{"question":"surf the internet","answer":"to browse various websites on the internet","guidance":"/sɜːf ði ˈɪntəˌnɛt/ - He likes to surf the internet in his free time.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737378438},{"question":"place","answer":"/pleɪs/: a particular position, point, or area in space; a location","guidance":"This is a nice place to have a picnic.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522031},{"question":"sports centre","answer":"A building where people can play sports","guidance":"[spɔːrts ˈsɛntər, \"He goes to the sports centre every weekend.\", \"The sports centre has a swimming pool.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"broken arm","answer":"a fracture or break in the arm bone","guidance":"[ˈbrəʊkən ɑːm] \"He had a broken arm after the fall.\" \"The doctor put a cast on his broken arm.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737383160},{"question":"asleep","answer":"In a state of sleep","guidance":"[əˈsliːp, \"The baby is asleep.\", \"He fell asleep during the movie.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"wind","answer":"/wɪnd/: the perceptible natural movement of the air, especially in the form of a current of air blowing from a particular direction","guidance":"The wind was so strong it knocked over the trash cans.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521310},{"question":"screen","answer":"A flat panel or area on an electronic device where images and data are displayed","guidance":"/'skriːn/ \"She watched the movie on a big screen.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242007},{"question":"special","answer":"Better, greater, or otherwise different from what is usual","guidance":"/'spɛʃəl/ \"She received a special gift for her birthday.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738155875},{"question":"scooter","answer":"a small two-wheeled vehicle","guidance":"He rode his scooter to school.","interval":37,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.5799997,"next_review":1740493028},{"question":"cloud","answer":"/klaʊd/: a visible mass of condensed watery vapour floating in the atmosphere, typically high above the general level of the ground","guidance":"The sky was covered with dark clouds.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399995,"next_review":1741013993},{"question":"smell","answer":"the faculty or power of perceiving odors or scents by means of the organs in the nose","guidance":"[smɛl, \"The smell of fresh bread filled the room.\", \"He has a keen sense of smell.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1738076992},{"question":"oil","answer":"a viscous liquid derived from petroleum, especially for use as a fuel or lubricant","guidance":"[ɔɪl, \"The car needs an oil change.\", \"Olive oil is often used in cooking.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344741},{"question":"nut","answer":"a fruit consisting of a hard or tough shell around an edible kernel","guidance":"/nʌt/: He likes to eat a nut as a snack.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737986924},{"question":"illness","answer":"A disease or period of sickness","guidance":"[ˈɪlnəs, \"She is recovering from a serious illness.\", \"Illness kept him from attending school.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"between","answer":"In the space separating two points","guidance":"[bɪˈtwiːn, \"She sat between her friends.\", \"The shop is between the bank and the post office.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"traffic","answer":"The movement of vehicles along a road","guidance":"[ˈtræfɪk] There is heavy traffic on the highway. Traffic lights control the flow of traffic.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737679303},{"question":"spend","answer":"to use time doing something","guidance":"[spɛnd] \"He spends a lot of time reading.\" \"She spent the afternoon shopping.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737382277},{"question":"digital","answer":"Involving or relating to the use of computer technology","guidance":"/'dɪdʒɪtəl/ \"She prefers digital books over printed ones.\"","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.4999998,"next_review":1738467401},{"question":"abacus","answer":"An ancient counting device","guidance":"/'æbəkəs/ \"Children learn to count using an abacus.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738241987},{"question":"guidebook","answer":"a book of information about a place","guidance":"She bought a guidebook before traveling to Paris.","interval":38,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599998,"next_review":1740578434},{"question":"toward","answer":"In the direction of","guidance":"[təˈwɔːd] She walked toward the door. The cat moved toward the window.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737679276},{"question":"visit websites","answer":"to access and view web pages","guidance":"/ˈvɪzɪt ˈwɛbˌsaɪts/ - She visits websites to find new recipes.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.54,"next_review":1737377790},{"question":"fountain","answer":"a structure that sends water up into the air","guidance":"[ˈfaʊntɪn, \"The fountain in the park is very beautiful.\", \"They threw coins into the fountain and made a wish.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"in no time","answer":"very quickly","guidance":"[ɪn nəʊ taɪm, \"We'll be there in no time.\", \"She finished her homework in no time.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"clinic","answer":"A place where people receive medical treatment","guidance":"[ˈklɪnɪk, \"She went to the clinic for a check-up.\", \"The clinic opens at 8 AM.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"post office","answer":"A place where mail is sent and received","guidance":"[poʊst ˈɒfɪs, \"She went to the post office to send a letter.\", \"The post office is closed on Sundays.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"along","answer":"Moving in a constant direction","guidance":"[əˈlɒŋ, \"They walked along the beach.\", \"The path runs along the river.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"trainer","answer":"a person who teaches skills to people or animals","guidance":"[ˈtreɪnər] The trainer helped me improve my running technique. She works as a dog trainer.","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644675},{"question":"sick","answer":"affected by physical or mental illness","guidance":"[sɪk] \"He felt sick after eating too much.\" \"She has been sick for a week.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737383291},{"question":"drum","answer":"a percussion instrument","guidance":"He played the drum in the school band.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521810},{"question":"game","answer":"An activity one engages in for amusement or fun","guidance":"/'ɡeɪm/ \"We played a fun board game last night.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242251},{"question":"downtown","answer":"the central part of a city","guidance":"We went downtown to visit the new museum.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737367718},{"question":"sandwich","answer":"an item of food consisting of two pieces of bread with a filling between them, eaten as a light meal","guidance":"[ˈsænwɪdʒ, \"I had a ham and cheese sandwich for lunch.\", \"She packed a sandwich for the picnic.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344327},{"question":"for a while","answer":"for a short period of time","guidance":"[fɔːr ə waɪl, \"He stayed with us for a while.\", \"Let's sit down and rest for a while.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.36,"next_review":1737645255},{"question":"sightseeing","answer":"the activity of visiting places of interest in a particular location","guidance":"/ˈsaɪtˌsiːɪŋ/ We went sightseeing in Paris.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737466456},{"question":"list","answer":"a number of connected items or names written consecutively","guidance":"[lɪst] I made a list of things to do. Can you add milk to the shopping list?","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"mud","answer":"wet, soft earth","guidance":"The kids played in the mud after the rain.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521898},{"question":"beside","answer":"At the side of","guidance":"[bɪˈsaɪd, \"He sat beside her.\", \"The lamp is beside the bed.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"chubby","answer":"Plump and rounded","guidance":"[ˈtʃʌbi, \"The baby has chubby cheeks.\", \"He was a chubby child.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"chili","answer":"a small hot-tasting pod of a variety of capsicum, used in sauces, relishes, and spice powders","guidance":"[ˈtʃɪli, She added some chili to the soup to give it a spicy flavor. The chili peppers were too hot for him to handle.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737776297},{"question":"cough","answer":"To expel air from the lungs with a sudden sharp sound","guidance":"[kɒf, \"He has a bad cough.\", \"She coughed loudly.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"suitcase","answer":"a large, rectangular container with a handle, used for carrying clothes and other personal belongings","guidance":"/'suːtkeɪs/ She packed her suitcase for the trip.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737466159},{"question":"cafe","answer":"a small restaurant selling light meals and drinks","guidance":"[ˈkæfeɪ, \"We had lunch at a small cafe by the beach.\", \"The cafe serves the best coffee in town.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644643},{"question":"smartphone","answer":"A mobile phone with advanced features","guidance":"/'smɑːrtfoʊn/ \"He checked his email on his smartphone.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738640706},{"question":"heard","answer":"Perceived with the ear","guidance":"[hɜːrd, \"She heard a noise.\", \"He heard the news on the radio.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"skull","answer":"the bone structure of the head","guidance":"The skull was found in the ancient ruins.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522333},{"question":"remarkable","answer":"worthy of attention","guidance":"Her performance was remarkable and received a standing ovation.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.2799997,"next_review":1737899418},{"question":"cycle tour","answer":"A trip made by bicycle","guidance":"[ˈsaɪkəl tʊr, \"They went on a cycle tour of the countryside.\", \"The cycle tour lasted three days.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"cling","answer":"to hold on tightly to something","guidance":"/klɪŋ/: The child would cling to his mother's leg when he was scared.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3999996,"next_review":1737986985},{"question":"gas","answer":"/ɡæs/: an air-like fluid substance which expands freely to fill any space available, irrespective of its quantity","guidance":"We need to refill the gas tank before our trip.","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.1799998,"next_review":1737813749},{"question":"playground","answer":"an outdoor area provided for children to play in, especially at a school or public park","guidance":"[ˈpleɪɡraʊnd, \"The children are playing in the playground.\", \"The playground has swings, slides, and a sandbox.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644194},{"question":"furry","answer":"covered with fur","guidance":"/ˈfɜri/: The cat's furry coat was soft and warm.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737986329},{"question":"stay","answer":"To remain in a particular place","guidance":"[steɪ] We decided to stay at a hotel. Please stay here while I go get help.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.5399997,"next_review":1737679494},{"question":"postcard","answer":"A card for sending a message by mail without an envelope","guidance":"[ˈpoʊstkɑːrd, \"She sent me a postcard from Paris.\", \"The postcard has a beautiful picture.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"design","answer":"a plan or drawing produced to show the look and function or workings of a building, garment, or other object before it is made","guidance":"[dɪˈzaɪn, \"The architect showed us the design for the new building.\", \"She has a talent for fashion design.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"street","answer":"a public road in a city or town, typically with houses and buildings on one or both sides","guidance":"[striːt, \"They live on a quiet street in the suburbs.\", \"The street was lined with trees.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"file","answer":"a collection of data or documents stored on a computer","guidance":"/faɪl/ - She saved the report as a PDF file.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737378057},{"question":"twist","answer":"to bend or turn something","guidance":"She had to twist the cap to open the bottle.","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.2599998,"next_review":1737813951},{"question":"passport","answer":"an official document for international travel","guidance":"Don't forget to bring your passport to the airport.","interval":38,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599996,"next_review":1740580529},{"question":"cinema","answer":"a theater where films are shown for public entertainment","guidance":"[ˈsɪnəmə, \"We went to the cinema to see the latest movie.\", \"The cinema was packed with people.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737643266},{"question":"bus stop","answer":"A designated place where a bus regularly stops","guidance":"[bʌs stɒp, \"She waited at the bus stop.\", \"The bus stop is near my house.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"lunch break","answer":"a period of time during which one stops working to eat lunch","guidance":"/lʌntʃ breɪk/ - He usually takes his lunch break at noon.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737378199},{"question":"restaurant","answer":"a place where people pay to sit and eat meals that are cooked and served on the premises","guidance":"[ˈrɛstərɒnt, \"We had dinner at a fancy restaurant.\", \"The restaurant is known for its excellent seafood.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"bus station","answer":"A place where buses start and end their routes","guidance":"[bʌs ˈsteɪʃən, \"We met at the bus station.\", \"The bus station is crowded.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"seafood","answer":"/ˈsiːfuːd/: shellfish and sea fish, served as food","guidance":"The restaurant is famous for its fresh seafood.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522449},{"question":"tour","answer":"a journey for pleasure in which several different places are visited","guidance":"/'tʊr/ We went on a tour of the city.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738939593},{"question":"passenger","answer":"A person who is traveling in a vehicle but is not driving it","guidance":"[ˈpæsɪndʒər] The bus was full of passengers. Each passenger must have a valid ticket.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737679336},{"question":"meat","answer":"/miːt/: the flesh of an animal (especially a mammal) as food","guidance":"She doesn't eat meat, she's a vegetarian.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522077},{"question":"diet","answer":"the kinds of food that a person, animal, or community habitually eats","guidance":"[ˈdaɪət, \"She is on a special diet to lose weight.\", \"A balanced diet is important for good health.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"watch videos","answer":"to view video content","guidance":"/wɒtʃ ˈvɪdɪəʊz/ - They watch videos on their tablet every evening.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737377376},{"question":"stage","answer":"a platform where performances are held","guidance":"The actors took their places on the stage.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3199997,"next_review":1737435281},{"question":"album","answer":"a collection of recordings issued as a single item","guidance":"They released their new album last month.","interval":34,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.4999995,"next_review":1740494812},{"question":"make","answer":"to form (something) by putting parts together or combining substances; create","guidance":"[meɪk, She likes to make her own clothes. He decided to make a cake for the party.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737776696},{"question":"preserve","answer":"to keep something in its original state","guidance":"They worked to preserve the historic building.","interval":12,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":1.9599997,"next_review":1737727110},{"question":"petrol station","answer":"A place where fuel is sold for vehicles","guidance":"[ˈpɛtrəl ˈsteɪʃən, \"He stopped at the petrol station.\", \"The petrol station is open 24 hours.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"view","answer":"The ability to see something","guidance":"[vjuː, \"The view from the window is beautiful.\", \"He has a good view of the stage.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"extinct","answer":"no longer in existence","guidance":"Dinosaurs have been extinct for millions of years.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3999999,"next_review":1737522225},{"question":"tracker","answer":"A device or program that monitors and records activity","guidance":"/'trækər/ \"The fitness tracker helps me keep track of my steps.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738553940},{"question":"opposite","answer":"Facing","guidance":"[ˈɒpəzɪt, \"The bank is opposite the post office.\", \"She sat opposite him.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"save","answer":"to store data for future use","guidance":"/seɪv/ - Don't forget to save your work before you close the document.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738939559},{"question":"thunder","answer":"/ˈθʌndə/: a loud rumbling or crashing noise heard after a lightning flash due to the expansion of rapidly heated air","guidance":"The thunder scared the dog.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741014638},{"question":"ghost","answer":"an apparition of a dead person which is believed to appear or become manifest to the living, typically as a nebulous image","guidance":"[ɡəʊst, \"They say the old house is haunted by a ghost.\", \"She dressed up as a ghost for Halloween.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737645103},{"question":"cave","answer":"/keɪv/: a large underground chamber, typically of natural origin, in a hillside or cliff","guidance":"We explored a dark cave during our hike.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1737607521},{"question":"among","answer":"Surrounded by","guidance":"[əˈmʌŋ, \"He was among friends.\", \"The house is hidden among the trees.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"called","answer":"Given a specified name","guidance":"[kɔːld, \"The dog is called Max.\", \"She called her friend.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"in the front of","answer":"At the forward part","guidance":"[ɪn ðə frʌnt ɒv, \"He sat in the front of the bus.\", \"The garden is in the front of the house.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"software","answer":"The programs and other operating information used by a computer","guidance":"/'sɒftwɛər/ \"He installed new software on his computer.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738241433},{"question":"pop","answer":"a genre of popular music","guidance":"She loves listening to pop music.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737607860},{"question":"police station","answer":"A building where police officers work","guidance":"[pəˈliːs ˈsteɪʃən, \"She reported the theft at the police station.\", \"The police station is nearby.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"garlic","answer":"a strong-smelling pungent-tasting bulb, used as a flavoring in cooking and in herbal medicine","guidance":"[ˈɡɑːrlɪk, She added garlic to the pasta sauce for extra flavor. The smell of garlic filled the kitchen.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737776785},{"question":"go online","answer":"to connect to the internet","guidance":"/ɡəʊ ɒnˈlaɪn/ - Many people go online to shop and read the news.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738941330},{"question":"terminal","answer":"a building where passengers transfer from ground transportation to the facilities that allow them to board airplanes, buses, etc.","guidance":"/'tɜːrmɪnl/ We waited at the terminal for our flight.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738940969},{"question":"emotion","answer":"a strong feeling such as love, fear, or anger","guidance":"/ɪˈmoʊʃən/: His voice was full of emotion when he told the story.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737987118},{"question":"sweet","answer":"/swiːt/: having the pleasant taste characteristic of sugar or honey; not salty, sour, or bitter","guidance":"She prefers sweet desserts over savory ones.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521143},{"question":"yogurt","answer":"a semi-solid sourish food prepared from milk fermented by added bacteria","guidance":"[ˈjəʊɡət, \"She eats yogurt with fruit for breakfast.\", \"Greek yogurt is thicker than regular yogurt.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344813},{"question":"weight","answer":"The measure of how heavy something is","guidance":"[weɪt, \"She is trying to lose weight.\", \"The weight of the package is 2 kg.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"sidewalk","answer":"a paved path for pedestrians","guidance":"They walked along the sidewalk to the park.","interval":32,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.4199996,"next_review":1740023233},{"question":"helicopter","answer":"a type of aircraft which derives both lift and propulsion from one or two sets of horizontally revolving rotors","guidance":"[ˈhɛlɪˌkɑptər, \"The helicopter landed on the hospital roof.\", \"They took a helicopter tour of the city.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737553745},{"question":"operation","answer":"A surgical procedure","guidance":"[ˌɒpəˈreɪʃən, \"He had an operation on his knee.\", \"The operation was successful.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"railroad","answer":"a track for trains","guidance":"The railroad connects the two cities.","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3399997,"next_review":1737349624},{"question":"violin","answer":"a string instrument played with a bow","guidance":"She plays the violin in the orchestra.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522041},{"question":"sunset","answer":"/ˈsʌnˌsɛt/: the time in the evening when the sun disappears below the horizon","guidance":"We watched the beautiful sunset from the beach.","interval":35,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.5799997,"next_review":1740582014},{"question":"hike","answer":"/haɪk/: a long walk, especially in the country or wilderness","guidance":"We went for a hike in the mountains last weekend.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737692963},{"question":"cast","answer":"To throw something forcefully","guidance":"[kæst, \"She cast the net into the sea.\", \"The actor was cast in the lead role.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"shame","answer":"a painful feeling of humiliation or distress","guidance":"[ʃeɪm] It's a shame you can't come to the party. He felt a deep sense of shame.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"fit","answer":"in good health, especially because of regular physical exercise","guidance":"[fɪt] He is very fit for his age. She goes jogging to stay fit.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"keyboard","answer":"A set of keys on a computer or typewriter","guidance":"/'kiːbɔːrd/ \"She typed the document on her keyboard.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242449},{"question":"camping","answer":"the activity of spending a vacation living in a camp, tent, or camper","guidance":"[ˈkæmpɪŋ, \"We are going camping in the mountains this weekend.\", \"Camping under the stars is a wonderful experience.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737553791},{"question":"fever","answer":"An abnormally high body temperature","guidance":"[ˈfiːvər, \"She has a high fever.\", \"The fever broke during the night.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"lightning","answer":"/ˈlaɪtnɪŋ/: the occurrence of a natural electrical discharge of very short duration and high voltage between a cloud and the ground or within a cloud","guidance":"The storm brought heavy rain and lightning.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.5599997,"next_review":1737521202},{"question":"muscle","answer":"A tissue composed of fibers capable of contracting","guidance":"[ˈmʌsəl, \"He pulled a muscle in his leg.\", \"Muscle strength is important for athletes.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"across","answer":"From one side to the other","guidance":"[əˈkrɒs, \"She walked across the street.\", \"The bridge goes across the river.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"jazz","answer":"a genre of music characterized by swing and blue notes","guidance":"They enjoy listening to jazz music.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737607891},{"question":"whole","answer":"all of; entire","guidance":"[həʊl, \"He ate the whole cake by himself.\", \"The whole class went on a field trip.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644295},{"question":"south","answer":"The direction that is to your right when you are facing the rising sun","guidance":"[saʊθ] They drove south for the winter. The birds migrate south every year.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737679508},{"question":"triathlon","answer":"a sporting contest consisting of three different events, typically swimming, cycling, and running","guidance":"[traɪˈæθlən] \"She trained for months to compete in the triathlon.\" \"The triathlon will take place next Saturday.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.4599998,"next_review":1738076941},{"question":"enter","answer":"to come or go into a place","guidance":"[ˈɛntər] \"Please enter the room quietly.\" \"You need a key to enter the building.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.5399997,"next_review":1738076261},{"question":"theatre","answer":"a building or outdoor area in which plays and other dramatic performances are given","guidance":"[ˈθɪətə, \"We went to the theatre to see a play.\", \"The theatre was full of people.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737645175},{"question":"roundabout","answer":"a road junction at which traffic moves in one direction around a central island to reach one of the roads converging on it","guidance":"[ˈraʊndəbaʊt, \"Take the second exit at the roundabout.\", \"There was a lot of traffic at the roundabout.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"noodles","answer":"/ˈnuːdlz/: a very thin, long strip of pasta or a similar flour paste, eaten with a sauce or in a soup","guidance":"I made a bowl of chicken noodle soup.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522243},{"question":"menu","answer":"a list of dishes available in a restaurant","guidance":"[ˈmɛnjuː, \"The waiter handed us the menu.\", \"The menu includes a variety of vegetarian options.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.52,"next_review":1737344899},{"question":"pizza","answer":"a dish of Italian origin consisting of a flat, round base of dough baked with a topping of tomatoes and cheese, typically with added meat or vegetables","guidance":"[ˈpiːtsə, \"We ordered a large pepperoni pizza.\", \"Pizza is a popular food for parties.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344228},{"question":"perfect","answer":"having no flaws or defects","guidance":"/ˈpɜːfɪkt/ - Her performance was perfect, and she received a standing ovation.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.4599998,"next_review":1737377747},{"question":"chimpanzee","answer":"a small, very intelligent African ape","guidance":"ˌtʃɪmpænˈziː/: The chimpanzee at the zoo was playing with toys.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737986911},{"question":"ham","answer":"meat from the upper part of a pig's leg salted and dried or smoked","guidance":"[hæm, She made a ham sandwich for lunch. The ham was sliced thin and served with mustard.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737776467},{"question":"at all","answer":"in any way or to any extent","guidance":"[æt ɔːl, \"I don't like this movie at all.\", \"Is there any chance at all of getting tickets?\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"musical","answer":"a play or movie with singing and dancing","guidance":"They went to see a musical on Broadway.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741013232},{"question":"instead","answer":"As an alternative","guidance":"[ɪnˈstɛd, \"She chose tea instead of coffee.\", \"He went to the park instead.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"dirt","answer":"/dɜːt/: a substance, such as mud or dust, that soils someone or something","guidance":"The kids came home covered in dirt after playing outside.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.5599997,"next_review":1737521420},{"question":"university","answer":"an educational institution designed for instruction, examination, or both, of students in many branches of advanced learning, conferring degrees in various faculties, and often embodying colleges and similar institutions","guidance":"[ˌjuːnɪˈvɜːsɪti, \"She is studying at a prestigious university.\", \"The university offers a wide range of courses.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"tourist","answer":"a person who is traveling or visiting a place for pleasure","guidance":"/'tʊrɪst/ The city is full of tourists in the summer.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738940867},{"question":"drug","answer":"A substance used as a medicine","guidance":"[drʌɡ, \"The doctor prescribed a new drug.\", \"He was arrested for drug possession.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"week","answer":"a period of seven days","guidance":"[wiːk] I will see you next week. There are seven days in a week.","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644118},{"question":"wrestle","answer":"to fight by holding and trying to throw the other person to the ground","guidance":"/ˈrɛsəl/: They would often wrestle on the living room floor.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737986036},{"question":"platform","answer":"a raised level surface","guidance":"The train arrived at platform 3.","interval":30,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.2599995,"next_review":1739849950},{"question":"chip","answer":"/tʃɪp/: a thin slice of food (typically potato) made crisp by being fried, baked, or dried and eaten as a snack","guidance":"Would you like some chips with your sandwich?","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737521401},{"question":"float","answer":"rest or move on or near the surface of a liquid without sinking","guidance":"[fləʊt, \"The boat began to float down the river.\", \"She watched the leaves float on the water.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737643299},{"question":"machine","answer":"a device with moving parts that performs a task","guidance":"/məˈʃiːn/ - The washing machine is broken and needs to be repaired.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738940691},{"question":"e-reader","answer":"A device for reading electronic books","guidance":"/ˈiːˌriːdər/ \"I use my e-reader to read books on the go.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1738155003},{"question":"exercise","answer":"physical activity to improve health and fitness","guidance":"[ˈɛksəsaɪz] \"She does exercise every morning.\" \"Regular exercise is important for staying healthy.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.4399998,"next_review":1737383692},{"question":"deaf","answer":"Lacking the power of hearing","guidance":"[dɛf, \"She was born deaf.\", \"He is deaf in one ear.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"dancer","answer":"a person who dances","guidance":"The dancer performed beautifully on stage.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741012925},{"question":"car park","answer":"A place where cars can be parked","guidance":"[kɑːr pɑːrk, \"He left his car in the car park.\", \"The car park is full.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"video","answer":"a recording of moving visual images","guidance":"They watched a music video on YouTube.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.4799998,"next_review":1737435921},{"question":"ginger","answer":"a hot, fragrant spice made from the rhizome of a plant, used in cooking and medicine","guidance":"[ˈdʒɪndʒər, She added ginger to the stir-fry for a spicy kick. Ginger tea is good for soothing a sore throat.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737776563},{"question":"mechanism","answer":"A system of parts working together in a machine","guidance":"/'mɛkənɪzəm/ \"The clock's mechanism was intricate.\"","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.1799996,"next_review":1738380989},{"question":"vacation","answer":"A period of time when you are not at work or school","guidance":"[vəˈkeɪʃən] We are planning a vacation to the beach. She took a two-week vacation in Europe.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737679592},{"question":"department","answer":"a division of a large organization such as a government, university, business, or shop, dealing with a specific area of activity","guidance":"[dɪˈpɑːtmənt, \"She works in the sales department.\", \"The department store has a wide range of products.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.36,"next_review":1737644585},{"question":"recording","answer":"the process of capturing sound","guidance":"The recording of the concert was excellent.","interval":36,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.2599998,"next_review":1740667535},{"question":"medicine","answer":"a substance used to treat illness or injury","guidance":"[ˈmɛdɪsɪn] \"She took some medicine for her cold.\" \"The doctor prescribed some medicine.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1738076729},{"question":"swimming pool","answer":"A pool for swimming","guidance":"[ˈswɪmɪŋ puːl, \"She swims in the swimming pool.\", \"The swimming pool is open in summer.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"engine","answer":"A machine with moving parts that converts power into motion","guidance":"/'ɛnʤɪn/ \"The car's engine is very powerful.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242027},{"question":"through","answer":"From one end to the other","guidance":"[θruː, \"She walked through the park.\", \"The tunnel goes through the mountain.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"under","answer":"In a lower position","guidance":"[ˈʌndər, \"The cat is under the table.\", \"The book is under the pillow.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"hunger","answer":"A feeling of discomfort or weakness caused by lack of food","guidance":"[ˈhʌŋɡər, \"He felt a pang of hunger.\", \"Hunger can affect concentration.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"tickle","answer":"to touch someone lightly with your fingers, making them laugh","guidance":"/ˈtɪkəl/: She tried to tickle her little brother to make him laugh.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1737986778},{"question":"opera","answer":"a dramatic work set to music","guidance":"They attended an opera at the famous theater.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741013935},{"question":"snake","answer":"/sneɪk/: a long limbless reptile which has no eyelids, a short tail, and jaws that are capable of considerable extension","guidance":"We saw a snake slithering through the grass.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737607665},{"question":"playhouse","answer":"A small house for children to play in","guidance":"[ˈpleɪhaʊs, \"The children are playing in the playhouse.\", \"The playhouse is in the garden.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"emergency","answer":"A serious, unexpected situation requiring immediate action","guidance":"[ɪˈmɜːrdʒənsi, \"Call 911 in case of an emergency.\", \"The hospital has an emergency room.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"ticket","answer":"a piece of paper or card that gives the holder a certain right, especially to enter a place, travel by public transport, or participate in an event","guidance":"/'tɪkɪt/ I bought a ticket for the concert.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737466448},{"question":"pancake","answer":"/ˈpænkeɪk/: a thin, flat cake of batter, fried on both sides in a pan and typically rolled up with a sweet or savoury filling","guidance":"We had pancakes with maple syrup for breakfast.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521793},{"question":"depart","answer":"to leave, especially in order to start a journey","guidance":"[dɪˈpɑrt, \"The train will depart at noon.\", \"They will depart for Paris tomorrow.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.2999997,"next_review":1737554172},{"question":"conversation","answer":"a talk between two or more people","guidance":"[ˌkɒnvəˈseɪʃən, \"We had a long conversation about our future plans.\", \"Their conversation was interrupted by a phone call.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.36,"next_review":1737644851},{"question":"survive","answer":"to continue to live or exist","guidance":"They had to find food and water to survive in the wilderness.","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.0199997,"next_review":1737813932},{"question":"above","answer":"At a higher level","guidance":"[əˈbʌv, \"The picture is above the fireplace.\", \"The plane flew above the clouds.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"catch","answer":"to capture or seize","guidance":"[kætʃ] I managed to catch the ball. Did you catch the train on time?","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"parking","answer":"The act of stopping and leaving a vehicle in a particular place","guidance":"[ˈpɑːkɪŋ] There is no parking allowed on this street. We found a parking spot near the entrance.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737679749},{"question":"enough","answer":"as much or as many as required","guidance":"[ɪˈnʌf, \"Do we have enough chairs for everyone?\", \"He didn't have enough money to buy the car.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737644376},{"question":"taste","answer":"the sensation of flavor perceived in the mouth and throat on contact with a substance","guidance":"[teɪst, \"The taste of the cake was amazing.\", \"She has a taste for spicy food.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344627},{"question":"fog","answer":"/fɒɡ/: a thick cloud of tiny water droplets suspended in the atmosphere at or near the earth's surface which obscures or restricts visibility","guidance":"Driving in the fog can be very dangerous.","interval":38,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599996,"next_review":1740840844},{"question":"lost","answer":"unable to find one's way","guidance":"He got lost in the unfamiliar city.","interval":38,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599998,"next_review":1740580659},{"question":"exist","answer":"to have actual being","guidance":"Many species exist in the rainforest.","interval":13,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.0399997,"next_review":1737814741},{"question":"nap","answer":"A short sleep, especially during the day","guidance":"[næp, \"He took a nap after lunch.\", \"She feels better after a nap.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"printer","answer":"A machine for printing text or pictures","guidance":"/'prɪntər/ \"The printer ran out of ink.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242065},{"question":"raincoat","answer":"A waterproof coat","guidance":"[ˈreɪnkoʊt, \"He wore a raincoat in the rain.\", \"The raincoat kept her dry.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"grill","answer":"/ɡrɪl/: a device on a cooker that radiates heat downwards for cooking food","guidance":"We decided to grill some burgers for lunch.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.5599997,"next_review":1737521871},{"question":"traffic lights","answer":"A set of lights that control traffic","guidance":"[ˈtræfɪk laɪts, \"The traffic lights turned red.\", \"He waited at the traffic lights.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"channel","answer":"a television or radio station","guidance":"She switched the channel to watch her favorite show.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522503},{"question":"walking tour","answer":"A tour taken on foot","guidance":"[ˈwɔːkɪŋ tʊr, \"They went on a walking tour of the city.\", \"The walking tour was very informative.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"console","answer":"A panel or unit accommodating a set of controls for electronic or mechanical equipment","guidance":"/'kɒnsoʊl/ \"He bought a new gaming console.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.3999999,"next_review":1738154954},{"question":"onion","answer":"/ˈʌnjən/: an edible bulb with a pungent taste and smell, composed of several concentric layers, used in cooking","guidance":"Chop the onion finely before adding it to the pan.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741014143},{"question":"subway","answer":"an underground railway system","guidance":"/'sʌbweɪ/ I took the subway to get to work.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737466222},{"question":"painting","answer":"a picture made with paint","guidance":"The museum has a famous painting by Van Gogh.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737608776},{"question":"intelligent","answer":"having or showing intelligence, especially of a high level","guidance":"/ɪnˈtɛlɪdʒənt/: She is very intelligent and always gets top grades in school.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737987501},{"question":"away","answer":"to or at a distance from a particular place","guidance":"[əˈweɪ, \"She moved away to a new city.\", \"The beach is just a mile away from here.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.3199997,"next_review":1737679283},{"question":"cooking","answer":"the practice or skill of preparing food by combining, mixing, and heating ingredients","guidance":"[ˈkʊkɪŋ, She enjoys cooking for her family every weekend. Cooking can be a relaxing and rewarding hobby.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737776679},{"question":"library","answer":"a building or room containing collections of books, periodicals, and sometimes films and recorded music for use or borrowing by the public or the members of an institution","guidance":"[ˈlaɪbrəri, \"She borrowed a book from the library.\", \"The library is open until 8 PM.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"forehead","answer":"The part of the face above the eyebrows","guidance":"[ˈfɔːrhɛd, \"He wiped his forehead.\", \"She has a high forehead.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"bottom","answer":"the lowest part or point of something","guidance":"[ˈbɒtəm, \"The bottom of the lake is very deep.\", \"He found the coin at the bottom of the box.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"fall off","answer":"to decrease in quantity or quality","guidance":"[fɔːl ɒf] Sales tend to fall off during the winter. Be careful not to fall off the ladder.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"fossil","answer":"the remains of a prehistoric organism","guidance":"The museum has a large collection of dinosaur fossils.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.5599997,"next_review":1737521967},{"question":"improve","answer":"to make or become better","guidance":"[ɪmˈpruːv] \"He wants to improve his English skills.\" \"Exercise can improve your overall health.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.4399998,"next_review":1737383833},{"question":"singing","answer":"the act of producing musical sounds with the voice","guidance":"She enjoys singing in the choir.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737608170},{"question":"museum","answer":"a building where objects of interest are displayed","guidance":"They visited the art museum on their trip.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737522459},{"question":"download videos","answer":"to transfer video files from the internet to a device","guidance":"/ˌdaʊnˈləʊd ˈvɪdɪəʊz/ - She downloaded videos to watch on the plane.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.54,"next_review":1737377293},{"question":"normal","answer":"Conforming to a standard; usual","guidance":"[ˈnɔːrməl, \"It's normal to feel nervous before an exam.\", \"Her temperature is normal.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"climate","answer":"the weather conditions in an area","guidance":"The climate in the desert is very dry.","interval":12,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":1.9599997,"next_review":1737728422},{"question":"at least","answer":"not less than; at the minimum","guidance":"[æt liːst, \"You should eat at least five servings of fruits and vegetables a day.\", \"It will take at least an hour to get there.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"hug","answer":"to hold someone tightly in your arms","guidance":"/hʌɡ/: She gave her friend a big hug when they met.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737987062},{"question":"store","answer":"a place where goods are kept for sale","guidance":"[stɔː, \"They opened a new store in the mall.\", \"The store is having a big sale this weekend.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737643730},{"question":"headache","answer":"a continuous pain in the head","guidance":"[ˈhɛdˌeɪk] \"I have a terrible headache.\" \"Stress can cause headaches.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737383245},{"question":"free time","answer":"time available for hobbies and other activities","guidance":"/friː taɪm/ - In his free time, he enjoys reading and hiking.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738940142},{"question":"bank","answer":"the land alongside or sloping down to a river or lake","guidance":"[bæŋk, \"They sat on the river bank and watched the boats.\", \"The bank of the river was covered in flowers.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"steak","answer":"high-quality beef taken from the hindquarters of the animal, typically cut into thick slices that are cooked by grilling or frying","guidance":"[steɪk, \"He ordered a medium-rare steak.\", \"Steak is often served with potatoes.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344597},{"question":"laugh","answer":"to make sounds with your voice that show you think something is funny","guidance":"/læf/: The joke made everyone laugh.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737986657},{"question":"visitor","answer":"Someone who visits a person or place","guidance":"[ˈvɪzɪtər] We had a visitor from out of town. The museum had many visitors last year.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737679606},{"question":"traveler","answer":"a person who is traveling or who often travels","guidance":"/'trævələ/ She is an experienced traveler.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737466884},{"question":"turn off","answer":"to deactivate a device","guidance":"/tɜːn ɒf/ - Please turn off the lights when you leave the room.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737378247},{"question":"highway","answer":"a main road, especially one connecting major towns or cities","guidance":"[ˈhaɪˌweɪ, \"They drove down the highway for hours.\", \"The highway was closed due to an accident.\"]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.54,"next_review":1737679712},{"question":"remember","answer":"to recall to the mind","guidance":"[rɪˈmɛmbər] I remember my first day at school. Do you remember where you put the keys?","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"virus","answer":"A malicious software program","guidance":"/'vaɪrəs/ \"The computer was infected with a virus.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242512},{"question":"narrow","answer":"of small width in relation to length","guidance":"[ˈnærəʊ, \"The path was too narrow for cars.\", \"They walked down the narrow alley.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.28,"next_review":1737645419},{"question":"record","answer":"a physical medium for storing music","guidance":"They bought a vinyl record of their favorite album.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599998,"next_review":1741013687},{"question":"download","answer":"To transfer data from one computer system to another","guidance":"/'daʊnloʊd/ \"She downloaded the latest software update.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.56,"next_review":1738155016},{"question":"omelette","answer":"/ˈɒmlɪt/: a dish of beaten eggs cooked in a frying pan and served plain or with a savoury or sweet topping or filling","guidance":"He made a cheese omelette for breakfast.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741014124},{"question":"tunnel","answer":"an artificial underground passage, especially one built through a hill or under a building, road, or river","guidance":"[ˈtʌnəl, \"The train went through a long tunnel.\", \"They are building a new tunnel under the river.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"pain","answer":"physical suffering or discomfort","guidance":"[peɪn] \"She felt a sharp pain in her back.\" \"The pain was unbearable.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737383109},{"question":"bush","answer":"a low plant with many branches","guidance":"They hid behind the bush to avoid being seen.","interval":7,"repetitions":5,"ease_factor":1.9199997,"next_review":1738162634},{"question":"careful","answer":"Making sure of avoiding potential danger, mishap, or harm","guidance":"/'kɛrfəl/ \"Be careful when crossing the street.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738241309},{"question":"balance","answer":"a state where things are of equal weight or force","guidance":"[ˈbæləns, \"She lost her balance and fell.\", \"You need to find a balance between work and play.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737645316},{"question":"feel","answer":"to experience an emotion or sensation","guidance":"[fiːl] I feel happy today. Do you feel the same way?","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"concert","answer":"a live music performance","guidance":"They attended a rock concert last night.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.1799998,"next_review":1737899489},{"question":"vine","answer":"a climbing plant","guidance":"The vine grew up the side of the house.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521738},{"question":"stomachache","answer":"pain in the stomach","guidance":"[ˈstʌməkˌeɪk] \"He had a stomachache after eating too much candy.\" \"A stomachache can be very uncomfortable.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737382570},{"question":"below","answer":"at a lower level or layer","guidance":"[bɪˈləʊ, \"The temperature dropped below freezing.\", \"The text below the image explains what it is.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"pronunciation","answer":"the way in which a word is pronounced","guidance":"[prəˌnʌnsiˈeɪʃən, \"Her pronunciation of French is excellent.\", \"The pronunciation of this word is tricky.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"steam","answer":"/stiːm/: the vapour into which water is converted when heated, forming a white mist of minute water droplets in the air","guidance":"The steam from the boiling water fogged up the windows.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.2399998,"next_review":1737435730},{"question":"speaker","answer":"A device that converts electrical signals into sound","guidance":"/'spiːkər/ \"The music played loudly through the speakers.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738241967},{"question":"later","answer":"at a time in the future","guidance":"[ˈleɪtər] I will call you later. See you later!","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.52,"next_review":1737644452},{"question":"laptop","answer":"A portable computer","guidance":"/'læptɒp/ \"I take my laptop to work every day.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1738242191},{"question":"dinosaur","answer":"a large extinct reptile","guidance":"The children were fascinated by the dinosaur exhibit.","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737521387},{"question":"plane","answer":"a vehicle designed for air travel","guidance":"They boarded the plane for their flight to Tokyo.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1737367788},{"question":"hotel","answer":"an establishment providing accommodation, meals, and other services for travelers and tourists","guidance":"[həʊˈtɛl, \"We stayed at a five-star hotel during our vacation.\", \"The hotel offers free breakfast to all guests.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"advice","answer":"guidance or recommendations concerning prudent future action","guidance":"[ədˈvaɪs] \"She gave me some good advice about my career.\" \"I need your advice on which course to take.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.36,"next_review":1737382706},{"question":"shop","answer":"a building or part of a building where goods or services are sold","guidance":"[ʃɒp, \"She went to the shop to buy some groceries.\", \"The shop is open from 9 AM to 6 PM.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"recover","answer":"To return to a normal state of health","guidance":"[rɪˈkʌvər, \"She is recovering from the flu.\", \"It took him a week to recover.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"cold","answer":"a common viral infection affecting the nose and throat","guidance":"[kəʊld] \"She caught a cold last week.\" \"A cold can make you feel very tired.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737645427},{"question":"driver","answer":"a person who drives a vehicle","guidance":"[ˈdraɪvər, \"The driver took a wrong turn.\", \"She is a skilled driver.\"]","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738941006},{"question":"chat to friends","answer":"to talk with friends","guidance":"/tʃæt tuː frɛndz/ - She likes to chat to friends during her free time.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.54,"next_review":1737377804},{"question":"snow","answer":"/snəʊ/: atmospheric water vapour frozen into ice crystals and falling in light white flakes or lying on the ground as a white layer","guidance":"The children were excited to see the snow falling.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7199998,"next_review":1737608841},{"question":"jungle","answer":"a dense forest in a tropical region","guidance":"They explored the jungle during their vacation.","interval":38,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.6599998,"next_review":1740841300},{"question":"curry","answer":"/ˈkʌri/: a dish of meat, vegetables, etc., cooked in an Indian-style sauce of strong spices and typically served with rice","guidance":"We had chicken curry for dinner last night.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741014616},{"question":"have to","answer":"to be required to","guidance":"[hæv tuː] I have to finish my homework. You have to wear a seatbelt in the car.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"temperature","answer":"/ˈtɛmprɪtʃə/: the degree or intensity of heat present in a substance or object","guidance":"The temperature dropped significantly overnight.","interval":14,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.4799998,"next_review":1737435898},{"question":"supermarket","answer":"a large self-service store selling foods and household goods","guidance":"[ˈsuːpəmɑːkɪt, \"We do our weekly shopping at the supermarket.\", \"The supermarket has a wide variety of products.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"jar","answer":"a wide-mouthed cylindrical container made of glass or pottery, especially one used for storing food","guidance":"[dʒɑːr, She opened a jar of pickles. The cookies were stored in a glass jar on the counter.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737776273},{"question":"tire","answer":"A rubber covering, typically inflated or surrounding an inflated inner tube, placed around a wheel to form a flexible contact with the road","guidance":"[taɪər] I need to replace the front tire of my bike. The car has a flat tire.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737679444},{"question":"have a rest","answer":"to take a break and relax","guidance":"[hæv ə rɛst] \"You should have a rest after working so hard.\" \"Let's have a rest before continuing our journey.\"","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.52,"next_review":1737382548},{"question":"hospital","answer":"an institution providing medical and surgical treatment and nursing care for sick or injured people","guidance":"[ˈhɒspɪtl, \"He was taken to the hospital after the accident.\", \"She works as a nurse at the local hospital.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"in front of","answer":"Directly before","guidance":"[ɪn frʌnt ɒv, \"He stood in front of the mirror.\", \"The car is parked in front of the house.\"]","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"band","answer":"a group of musicians who play together","guidance":"The band played at the local club.","interval":40,"repetitions":4,"ease_factor":2.7399998,"next_review":1741013909},{"question":"noodle","answer":"a strip, ring, or tube of pasta or a similar dough","guidance":"[ˈnuːdl, \"She cooked a delicious noodle soup.\", \"Noodles are a staple in many Asian cuisines.\"]","interval":1,"repetitions":1,"ease_factor":2.6,"next_review":1737344995},{"question":"headphone","answer":"A pair of small speakers worn over or in the ears","guidance":"/'hɛdˌfoʊn/ \"She put on her headphones to listen to music.\"","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399999,"next_review":1738241462},{"question":"fried","answer":"cooked in hot fat or oil","guidance":"[fraɪd, She ordered fried chicken for dinner. The fried fish was crispy and delicious.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737776510},{"question":"buy clothes","answer":"to purchase garments","guidance":"/baɪ kləʊðz/ - I need to buy clothes for the upcoming winter season.","interval":16,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.7999997,"next_review":1738940513},{"question":"race","answer":"a competition of speed","guidance":"[reɪs] She won the race. The race will start at 10 AM.","interval":0,"repetitions":0,"ease_factor":2.5,"next_review":0},{"question":"chat online","answer":"to converse with others over the internet","guidance":"/tʃæt ɒnˈlaɪn/ - They often chat online with their friends after school.","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.62,"next_review":1737378543},{"question":"cracker","answer":"a thin, crisp wafer often eaten with cheese or other savory toppings","guidance":"[ˈkrækər, He spread some cheese on the cracker and took a bite. The children enjoyed eating crackers with their soup.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1737776943},{"question":"chef","answer":"a professional cook, typically the chief cook in a restaurant or hotel","guidance":"[ʃɛf, The chef prepared a delicious meal for the guests. The restaurant's chef is known for his innovative dishes.]","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.54,"next_review":1737776385},{"question":"position","answer":"A place where someone or something is located or has been put","guidance":"/'pəˈzɪʃən/ \"He found a comfortable position to sit.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.5799997,"next_review":1738554006},{"question":"toothache","answer":"pain in a tooth or teeth","guidance":"[ˈtuːθˌeɪk] \"He went to the dentist because of a toothache.\" \"A toothache can be very painful.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.6999998,"next_review":1738077346},{"question":"memory","answer":"The faculty by which the mind stores and remembers information","guidance":"/'mɛməri/ \"He has a good memory for names.\"","interval":15,"repetitions":3,"ease_factor":2.6399996,"next_review":1738156131},{"question":"make sure","answer":"to ensure something happens","guidance":"[meɪk ʃʊə] \"Make sure you lock the door.\" \"She made sure to check her work.\"","interval":6,"repetitions":2,"ease_factor":2.4599998,"next_review":1738075766}]